Zeid A. Diez: Software Engineer

zeidlaidiez@gmail.com - (253) 266-4756

<u>LinkedIn</u> - Portfolio - GitHub

SUMMARY

Computer programmer in love with efficiency and numbers. Fluent in English, Spanish, Business and Nerd. One of my greatest assets is the ability to mend any disconnect between executives, engineers and production. Years of experience as a business analyst and later years as a project manager have allowed me to identify and break down processes down to each moving part.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

General: Bilingual (English & Spanish both native proficiency), Self-Starter, Analytical Front End: JavaScript, React, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Vercel and other PaaS Deployment

Back End and Others: Node, Various SQL, Express, Webpack, GitHub, Heroku, Unit Testing, RESTful APIs

EXPERIENCE

Thinkful/Bloc - Engineering Immersion Projects

2020-2021

Pandemic Dog Walking - A full stack app to assist users in scheduling dog walks

- Utilized SQL in storing user data and appointment data, with node.js and express on the backend and native react frontend.
- Full stack app utilizing PERN stack

ReadNext - Reader's to-do list, a full stack solution

- A database driven to-do list meant to facilitate the task of choosing what to read next.
- HTML and CSS with DOM Manipulation using jQuery

Metia (Bellevue, WA) 2018 - 2019

Project Management

- Led and administered daily meetings to assess bandwidth of various content delivery teams.
- Routed all new projects and ensured bandwidth of resources allowed for desired deadlines.
- Periodically ensured that progress in all current projects was as expected, and adjusted resources as needed to meet goals.

Intech Consulting (Kent, WA)

2017 - 2018

IT Consultant

- Managed Active Directory, SQL and AWS Services for large companies.
- Utilized six sigma methodologies when managing projects.
- Built hundreds of custom-ordered computers for various clients, with varying purposes from video gaming to number crunching.

West Corp (Middleton, WI)

2012 - 2017

Business Analyst

- Created, trained and implemented production-ready CRM environment.
- Shadowed employees in large call centers to find process inefficiencies, which I then resolved.
- Developed complex call forecasting and staffing forecasting applications to suit the goals of a call center.

EDUCATION

Thinkful/Bloc 2020 - 2021

Engineering Immersion

• An intense full-time immersion program for software engineers, focusing on real-world app building and encompassing full stack development.